RG 004:105, Old Lyme Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Old Lyme Probate Court records
1821-1974
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Old Lyme District)
35.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1821-1974; Probate files, 1830-1945.
RG004_105
1912-007 and 2014-008
Historical Note
Old Lyme, New London County, Set off from Saybrook, February 13, 1665, Town established in May 1855 as South Lyme, name changed in 1857 to Old Lyme, Parent Town: Lyme
The Old Lyme (South Lyme) Probate District was constituted in May 1855 from the Lyme Probate District. Name of probate district changed from Lyme to Old Lyme, July 24, 1868. Probate records concerning Old Lyme, from May 1, 1666 to June 4, 1830, are in New London; records from June 4, 1830 to date, are in Old Lyme. The Old Lyme Probate District merged with the East Lyme, Montville, and Salem Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #32 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Lyme, Montville, Old Lyme, and Salem.
Town of Old Lyme, Probate District chronology:
May 1855 - January 4, 2011, Old Lyme District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region #32 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1821-1974. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1830-1945. Includes files from Lyme District from 1830 to 1868. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1830-1945 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2013-008 are numbered from 1 to 47.
Probate files in accession 1912-007 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-007 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Lyme; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Old Lyme
Places:
Lyme (Conn.); Old Lyme (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2014-008, Record books, 1821-1974, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files from 1921-1945 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-6, 1829-1915, probate files, 1830-1880; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-007 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): September 13, 1912 (1830-1905); October 18, 1924 (1851-1920); December 13, 1928 (1876-1927); March 27, 1946 (1923-1945). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2014-008 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on July 22, 2013.
Container List
- Record books, 1821-1974; 24 cubic feet (47 volumes); 2014-008
  - Records, 1821-1849 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1849-1866 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1866-1887 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1887-1900 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1900-1909 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1909-1915 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1915-1922 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1922-1926 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1923-1931 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1831-1845 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1936-1939 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1939-1945 (Volume 12)
  - Orders and decrees, 1939-1948 (Volume 13)
  - Bonds, 1939-1961 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1943-1949 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1949-1950 (Volume 16)
  - Orders and decrees, 1948-1956 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1950-1954 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1954-1956 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1956-1957 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1957-1958 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1958-1959 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1958-1961 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1958-1960 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1959-1961 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1962-1963 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1963-1964 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1963-1964 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1964-1965 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1963-1865 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1965 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1965-1966 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1966-1967 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1965-1967 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1967-1968 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1968 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1968-1969 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1969 (Volume 38)
  - Records, 1969 (Volume 39)
  - Records, 1970 (Volume 40)
  - Records, 1970-1971 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1971 (Volume 42)
  - Records, 1972 (Volume 43)
  - Records, 1972-1973 (Volume 44)
  - Records, 1973 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1973-1974 (Volume 46)
  - Records, 1974 (Volume 47)
- Probate files, 1830-1945; 11.5 cubic feet; 1912-007
  - Abrams - Bacon, D. (Drawer 1)
  - Bacon, E. - Bartlett (Drawer 2)
  - Bartman - Brevoort (Drawer 3)
  - Broatch - Bugbee (Drawer 4)
  - Bulkeley - Chadwick, C. (Drawer 5)
  - Chadwick, D. - Champion, F. (Drawer 6)
  - Champion, G. - Champlain (Drawer 7)
  - Chaplain - Colli (Drawer 8)
  - Comstock - Deacon (Drawer 9)
  - Dean - Ebell (Drawer 10)
  - Eddie - Ely, V. (Drawer 11)
  - Ely, W. - Gilbo (Drawer 12)
  - Gillett - Griswold, D. (Drawer 13)
  - Griswold, E. - Griswold, L. (Drawer 14)
  - Griswold, M. - Harding (Drawer 15)
  - Harris - Hoskins (Drawer 16)
  - Howard - Jewitt (Drawer 17)
  - Johnson - Lamott (Drawer 18)
  - Lane - Latham (Drawer 19)
  - Lay - Lewis (Drawer 20)
  - Littlefield - Lougee (Drawer 21)
  - Luddington - Marvin (Drawer 22)
  - Mason - Miller (Drawer 23)
  - Milliard - Morley (Drawer 24)
  - Moss, A. - Moss, D. (Drawer 25)
  - Moss, E. - Noyes, P. (Drawer 26)
  - Noyes, Q. - Rowland (Drawer 27)
  - Royce - Swan (Drawer 28)
  - Swaney - Zero; Miscellaneous (Drawer 29)
- Inventory Control Book, 1830-1945; T003073
  Index of the four accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1912-007
  Also known as the Godard Digest